<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: thor | Mitch Crowe]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.mitchcrowe.com/blog/categories/thor/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.mitchcrowe.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-16T20:12:58-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.mitchcrowe.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mitch Crowe]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[crowe.mitch@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rubynu—A scaffold generator for ruby projects]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.mitchcrowe.com/blog/2011/12/12/rubynu-a-scaffold-generator-for-ruby-projects/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-12T12:17:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.mitchcrowe.com/blog/2011/12/12/rubynu-a-scaffold-generator-for-ruby-projects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Creating my preferred scaffolding for new ruby projects by hand has gotten old. Sure, there are tools out there like bundler's <code>bundle gem</code> to do this for you, but they aren't flexible enough to meet everybody's preferences. I want something as flexible as my tastes are fickle, something I can change the template to on a whim.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So, I built <code>rubynu</code>. It's a Thor script that leans heavily on Thor's directory templating abilities. Thor is amazing for this kind of generator: instead of building everything programatically, you can define an entire directory template&mdash;using erb templating for file contents, file names, and even directory structure. This kind of template makes it stupid easy to add new files, or to do any number of structural changes to it without touching the script itself. By Thor's Hammer!</p>

<p>Currently, <code>rubynu</code> builds a project with the standard structure:</p>

<pre><code>bin/
lib/
  %app_name%.rb
  %app_name%/
spec/
Gemfile
README.markdown 
</code></pre>

<p>It also sets up rspec, with a <code>spec_helper</code>, <code>.rspec</code>, and a pending spec; RVM with an <code>.rvmrc</code>; git with a <code>.gitignore</code>; as well as some useful scaffolded code.</p>

<p>For usage, installation instructions, and to view the source, check out <a href="https://github.com/mcrowe/Rubynu">rubynu on github</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paranoid - A backup script for when the world's out to get you]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.mitchcrowe.com/blog/2011/11/07/paranoid-a-backup-script-for-when-the-world-slash-s-out-to-get-you/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-07T16:28:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.mitchcrowe.com/blog/2011/11/07/paranoid-a-backup-script-for-when-the-world-slash-s-out-to-get-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I've put a ton of effort into a personal project, I tend to get paranoid that I'll somehow find a way to toast it. I know, I know, git, github, and time machine already have my back. Sometimes that's just not enough, though, and I find myself periodically making manual copies of important projects to a backup directory. Whether I need it or not, having hardcopy snapshots just makes me feel better.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So I wrote paranoid, a Thor script for those paranoid but lazy coders like me. Sure, we could use a one-liner <code>cp -rf</code>, or <code>rsync</code> command, but there are a few niceties that paranoid gives you:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Timestamped backups, so they are never written over, and you can easily revisit a snapshot of the project at any given time.</p></li>
<li><p>You can specify files to exclude from a backup on a project-by-project basis by modifying a <code>.backupignore</code> file. This allows you to ignore <code>.git</code> and <code>.bundle</code> directories as well as any project specific files such as large data dumps that you might not want copied over and over.</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Install paranoid</h3>

<p>Paranoid is a <a href="https://github.com/wycats/thor">Thor</a> script, and you will have to install Thor first. Then, clone the repository and run: <code>thor install paranoid.thor</code></p>

<h3>Make your projects paranoid</h3>

<p>In your project root directory, run: <code>thor paranoid init</code>
This creates a default <code>.backupignore</code> file. This file defines patterns for files you don't want to backup in this project. You can now add or remove patterns as you wish.</p>

<h3>Backup a paranoid project</h3>

<p>In your project root directory, run: <code>thor paranoid backup</code>
This rsyncs your project to the <code>~/.paranoid</code> directory, ignoring any files matching the patterns in the project's <code>.backupignore</code> file.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
